<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
	<sections>
		<section name="home and news" image="home">
			<info>Recent updates:^^tutorials - 8/12/02^components - 8/12/02</info>
			<textBlock>Welcome to the new version of 27Bobs, updated to utilize some of the new features of Flash MX.  I thought the theme of a sketchbook or a drawing board for the new interface was appropriate given the purpose of this site.^^Keep an eye out for Flash MX Studio, out in July from Friends of ED.  I contributed three chapters to this book in which I discuss the drawing API and using it to code 3D in Flash.</textBlock>
		</section>
		<section name="about me" image="me">
			<textBlock>I studied in London to become an actor, which I did for several years, working in repertory theater and in national tours.  After moving to New York City to pursue the Great White Way, both as a writer and actor, my side job introduced me to Flash.  It hooked me from the start, appealing to both my reason and my creativity like nothing before it.  I now work for Daedalus Media here in NYC, using Flash to create offline presentations.  27Bobs is my playground.</textBlock>
		</section>
		<section name="links" image="links">
			<info>Here are a few sites that I've been involved in creating.  Most of my work is for offline presentation, but I still enjoy putting what I can onto the Web.</info>
			<link>
				<title>Imagescore Music</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A site for a company specializing in the creation of commercial jingles and film scoring.  The goal was to create an interface to point up the diversity of the musical styles offered.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Daedalus Media</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Daedalus Media creates customized presentations for corporate clients.  The site highlights the benefits of using Flash for screenshows.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Some Snap!</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A musical I'm involved in writing.  This site was an advertisement put together in one evening.  I intend to update it at some point with more content and information on the show.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>27Bobs version 1</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Explore a spaceport and spacecraft to discover the content of my initial site.  My first really big Flash experiment and a lot of fun to put together.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>27Bobs version 2</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>I created this over a weekend when I began exploring 3D navigation techniques.  Very simple to update (as opposed to the previous version), which was my main goal.</info>
			</link>
		</section>
		<section name="games & diversions" image="games">
			<info>Some games, some coding experiments, a fun time to be had by all.</info>
			<link>
				<title>Cassie</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>My first Flash experiment and a tribute to my favorite canine, who just happens to be the cutest dog ... ever.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Fluppets</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>I've always been a big Jim Henson fan, so I was excited to attempt this interactivity experiment.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>MazeMaker</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>I don't recall what prompted this experiment, but I used a variation as a navigation tool in the first version of my site.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>SphereCage</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>&lt;shameless plug&gt; A game I created for Friends of ED's Flash MX Studio due out in July. &lt;/shameless plug&gt;  It's 3D Pong, and pretty tough to beat.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Wailing Chamber</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>After I completed MazeMaker, I wanted to make a dungeon game similar to those I played when I was younger.  Retro is cool!</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>StarFlight</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Creating an interactive starfield was my first 'non-button' ActionScript experiment.  I found it hypnotic to watch the planets go by.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Pixel Screen</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Just wanted to see if I could pull information out of a picture file and recreate a pixelated image in Flash.  Transitions were easy after that.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>wobbly eyes</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>This was an early experiment into using the drawing API and specifically its gradient matrix.  Then I just had fun making it wobble.  Except for the reflection map applied, this is all code.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Director 3D Maze</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>I'm teaching myself Director and Shockwave3D at the moment.  This 3D maze is an improved, real-3D version of my earlier maze experiments.</info>
			</link>
		</section>
		<section name="stories & animations" image="stories">
			<info>I love storytelling, in many of its forms.  I only wish I had more time to explore it.  Here are a few attempts.</info>
			<link>
				<title>The Clew</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>This was an experiment in 'linked storytelling', where each creator would pick up the thread of the previous episode and spin it in a new direction.  Neat idea, but nobody bit.  Ah, well.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Sammy</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A children's book I was working on while I was teaching myself Illustrator and Photoshop.  My first computer generated imagery.  It's interesting to note stages of development."</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Theseus</title>
				<info>This project has been brewing for over a decade in many different forms.  Right now, it's a musical retelling of the classic Greek myth.  With so much time spent in developing it, it's very close to my heart.  The site is still in development.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Some Snap!</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A musical exploring the life of a Tin Pan Alley and Hollywood lyricist from the 20's and 30's.  Fascinating time, fascinating individual.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>The Wyvern's Claw</title>
				<info>My film noir fantasy series.  I love fantasy, love classic detective novels and movies.  I figured it was about time to merge the two.  The completed first episode should be online within the month.</info>
			</link>
		</section>
		<section name="downloads & components" image="downloads">
			<info>I've created quite a few smart clips (Flash 5) and components (Flash MX).  Most I've been able to make available for download here.</info>
			<link>
				<title>particle system</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Here's a smart clip that will allow the easy creation of vector particle effects.  A lot of fake 3D, but effective and extremely simple to customize.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>starfield</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A drag and drop smart clip that will create a moving starfield that's all of 3Kb.  Both versions of my site used this.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>3D Actionscript library</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A library I was working on to explore the new drawing methods in Flash MX.  Not too fast, but offers a lot of functionality.  A help file is included to show the syntax.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Biped Animator</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>My first Animator smart clip.  You can use this interface to animate movement of biped skeletons (either your own or those provided).  Lots of fun.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Face Animator</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>After the Biped Animator, the next natural step was to provide animation for a face.  I added a lot of extra functionality for this one, and the result is a much more robust tool.  Still a lot of fun.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>SphereAnimator</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>This Animator brought in the additional element of a 3rd dimension.  Spheres were used to better simulate 3D, but any symbol could be substituted.  Nominated for the FlashForward Film Festival in Amsterdam.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>PolyAnimator</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>The logical conclusion for my Animator smart clips.  This Animator allowed for the manipulation and animation of solid and texture filled polygon models.  It was my first attempt at many 3D coding concepts, and I'm still proud of the result.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>toolbox</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>A component that allows the easy creation of toolboxes or tool palettes for Flash interfaces.  I made this component to simplify the creation of component custom UI's.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>xy scatter chart</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>My first component.  We use xy scatter charts quite a bit at Daedalus, so I made this component to make it easy to create and animate our charts.  Unfortunately, I can't make this available at this time.</info>
			</link>
		</section>
		<section name="tutorials" image="tutorials">
			<info>Not too much to see here yet, though I plan to spend more time creating online tutorials for Flash MX.  You'll find updates here.</info>
			<link>
				<title>arrays and recorded motion</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Here's a simple tutorial for anyone who is not yet familiar with arrays.  The result of the tutorial is the recording and playback of user-defined motion on screen.</info>
			</link>
			<link>
				<title>Illustrator gradient mesh</title>
				<url></url>
				<info>Someone posted a question in the were-here forums about using Illustrator's gradient mesh tool to create something realistic.  I made this file in an evening to show how it might be achieved.  Not so much a tutorial as a display of the stages of creation.</info>
			</link>
		</section>
	</sections>
</xml>